In a world where everyone can only tell the truth... This guy can lie.
The Invention of Lying is a comedy, fantasy,
romance film directed by Ricky Gervais.
Set in a world where the concept of lying doesn't exist, a loser changes
his lot when he invents lying and uses it to get ahead.
Mark Bellison, played by Ricky Gervais.
Anna McDoogles, played by Jennifer Garner.
Greg Kleinschmidt, played by Louis C.K..
Brad Kessler, played by Rob Lowe.
Frank Fawcett, played by Jonah Hill.
Anthony James, played by Jeffrey Tambor.
The Invention of Lying is a 2009 romantic comedy fantasy film written and directed by
comedian Ricky Gervais and writer Matthew Robinson in their directorial debuts.
The film stars Gervais as the first human with the ability to lie
in a world where people can only tell the truth.
The cast also includes Jennifer Garner, Jonah Hill, Louis C.K., Jeffrey Tambor,
Fionnula Flanagan, Rob Lowe, Philip Seymour Hoffman and Tina Fey.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2009, and
was released in the United States on October 2, 2009, by Warner Bros.
Pictures and Focus Features.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $32.7
million against a $18.5 million budget.
The film explores themes of lie, religion, lies.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.